Finding Aid for the Miscellaneous Manuscripts Collection LSC.0100
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Author Identified
  - Clark, Tom. Correspondence., 1974-1984.; (21 items, 17pp. [holograph and typescript]). (Box 283, Folder 3)
    1 letter to Alice Notley Berrigan (1974) and 11 letters from Harcourt, Brace, Jovanovich Publishers.
    Purchased: Arunel.
  - Clarke, Dwight L. Big silver. undated 57 pages. Typescript. (Box 25)
    Gift: Author, 1954 January 27.
    An account of the California Rand Silver mine, usually referred to as the "Big Silver."
  - Clayton, A. To [William E. Chandler] Washington. 1833 March 12 1 page. A.L.S. (Box 9)
  - Cobbe, Frances Power, 1822-1904. Signed correspondence. V.p., n.d. 11 items. Holograph. (Box 6)
  - Coffield, Glen. Collection of pamphlets and ephemera, written and mimeographed by Glen Coffield. Portland, Oregon. 1950- 115 items. (Box 24)
    With this: correspondence between Glen Coffield and Lawrence Clark Powell, 1949-. 8 pieces.
  - Coffin, Tristam. To Joseph Smith, Newburyport, Mass. 1806 Jan 7 Holograph signed. (Box 4)
  - Collier, John, 1901-1980. Correspondence. 1931 1 folder. (Box 7)
    Three holograph signed letters to jacob Schwartz, Ashmansworth near Newbury, August-December, 1931.
  - Collier, John A[llen], 1787-1873. To Gillespie's Lottery Office, Chenango Point [New York]. 1820 September 11 1 p. A.L.S. (Box 9)
    Letter requesting one half ticket in the National Lottery.
  - Connvell family. [Correspondence]. 1844-1853 3 letters. (Box 8)
    Purchased from Zeitline, 1951 September 17.
    Letters of Charles and LaFayette Connvell to their parents in Connersville, Indiana from Cincinnati, Ohio.
  - Cowper, Henry Swaison, 1865-1941. Correspondence and papers. 1918-1933 (Box 7)
    Removed from Cumberland and Westmoreland Archaeological Society. Transactions. New Series, v. 1- 40, 1901-1940.
  - Clarkson, Thomas, 1760-1846. Letters to various persons. V.p., v.d. 1807 July 28 1 item. Holograph. (Box 5)
    1 letter to James Pemberton.
  - Clodd, Edward, 1840-1930. Letters to Charles Ganz. v.p. 1900-1932 13 items. Holograph. (Box 12)
    The two letters written in 1932 are from Phyllis Clodd, widow of Edward Clodd.
  - Cole, Cornelius. Letter to the Honorable Winslow S. Pierce, California State Comptroller., 1852 28 October.; (1 item, 4pp. [holograph, signed]). (Box 289, Folder 10)
    Purchase: Yerba Buena.
  - Cook, Theodore Pease, 1844-1916. Correspondence to John Thompson Hoffman, Albany, New York and Utica, New York. 1870 December 7 and 1871 November 11 2 letters. Holograph signed. (Box 16)
    Letter of 1870, of resignation from the post of Military Secretary to the staff of Hoffman, Governor of New York, and remarks of appreciation. Letter of 1871 mentions Colonel James Fisk and the defeat of the Democratic party in state elections.
  - Cooke, Bates, 1787-1841. To the editor of the Congressional Globe, Washington. 1831 December 31 and 1832 June 20 2 letters. A.L.S. (Box 9)
  - Cooke, Richard. Correspondence. (Box 5)
    Removed from: Horsley, J. N., Place names in Kent, Maidenstone, 1921.
    2 als. 1 transcript of letter by Cooke. 1 transcript of a letter to Cooke. 1 illegible and unidentifiable autograph manuscript note.
  - Conference Board of Associated Research Councils. Letters to Robert M. Glendinning., 1953-1962. (Box 199, Folder 4)
    re the advisory selection committee for Fullbright awards.
  - Conness, John, 1821-1909. To Wilson, New York. 1869 June 13 4 p. holograph signed. (Box 4)
    Purchased from Charles Hamilton, July 5, 1955.
    Concerning Southern California and the Southern Pacific Railroad.
  - Constable & Co., Ltd., publishers, London. Correspondence. 1 item. Typescript. (Box 12)
    1 letter to Coulson Kernahan, July 22, 1920.
  - Constable, John. Letter to Mr. Carpenter., 1830 August 20. (Box 192, Folder 21)
  - Cooke, General Sir George, 1768-1837. 10 letters to Cooke from his brother H.C. Vernon Graham., 1802 & 1808.; (10 items, 10 leaves). (Box 193, Folder 6)
    2 letters incomplete.
  - Corcoran, W[illiam] W[ilson] 1789-1888. To Messrs. Blair and Rives, Washington. 1834 November 27 1 p. A.L.S. (Box 9)
  - Cornell, Alonzo B., 1832-1904. To Mr. Harriot, "Longview," Yonkers, New York. 1887 June 20 1 p. Holograph signed. (Box 16)
    Concerning a Mr. Townsend and his article. Cornell was retired Governor of new York at this time.
  - Corso, Gregory. Material of the spirit., n.d. (Box 193, Folder 4)
    Typescript and proofs.
    Gift of Allan Kurtzman.
  - Corwin, Tho[mas] 1794-1865. To N. G. Hamend, Lebanon [Ohio]. 1827 October 2 1 l. A.L.S. (Box 9)
    Aldine Purchase
  - Cowell, Henry, 1897-1965. Works, piano. 7 scores. (Box 23)
    Oversize. Contents: Chiaroscuro, episode No. II, Episode No. III, It isn't it, Polyphonica, Some music, and Vestiges.
  - Crabbe, Buster, 1908-1983. Aqua Parade of 1949. (Box 5, Folder 59)
  - Crabbe, George, 1754-1832. Autograph. N.p, n.d. 1 item. Holograph. (Box 5)
    Removed from: Crabbe's life and poems. PR 4510 A5C8 v.1
  - Craig, Hector, 1775-1842. Letters to David H. Gillespie and Samuel L Southhard. 1822 March 2 and 1824 January 17 2 letters. A.L.S. (Box 9)
  - Crawford vs. Los Angeles County Superior Court., 1980. (Box 199, Folder 3)
    Court case re desegregation in Los Angeles Unified School District.
    Gift of John Caughey.
  - Crawford, Francis Marion, 1854-1909. Papers. 8 items. Holograph and typescript. (Box 30)
    1 letter to Theodore Watts-Dunton, 1907 July 9. Document, 1908 January 17: agreement between Butterick Pub. Co., New York, and The Author's Syndicate, London, to buy the serial rights of Crawford's "Stradella;" with Theodore Dreiser's signature as witness. Document, 1909 April 2: agreement between Crawford and William Waldorf Astor, publisher of the Pall Mall Magazine, for the serial rights of "The undesirable governess".
  - Crawford, John Wallace. 1 typed poem, signed. (Box 5)
    Removed from: Crawford, John Wallace. Whar' the Hand o' God is seen. PS 1469 C3w.
  - Crawford, W. S. Correspondence. 1896-1897 100 numb. l. A.L.S. (letterpress copy) (Box 8)
    letters relating to the operation of his farm in San Bernardino County.
  - Croswell E[dwin] 1797-1871. To Armsby, [New York]. 1856 June 20 1 page. A.L.S. (Box 9)
  - Croly, George, 1780-1860. Correspondence, signed. Circa 1815-1860 37 items. Holograph. (Box 29)
    With these: 2 leaves of manuscript poetry by Croly: 1. Croly's version of the 19th Psalm, 1860 April 25. 2. A fragment, untitled.
  - Crouch, Winston W. Commission for the Reorganization of the Government of the City of Los Angeles., 1950-1952. (Box 188, Folder 8)
    Papers re "Little Hoover Commission."
  - Crowley, Aleister, 1875-1947. Papers. Circa 1923 (Box 15)
    Purchase Sims, 1951.
    1) Fragment 1: "From the book of the golden precepts." "The voice of silence" and commentary. Typescript carbon copy, 113 p. bound. 2) Bound typescript, no title. "The number of the bok is 333." no pagination. 3) Preliminary analysis of Liber LXV." 95 p. typescript, carbon copy. 4) See Box 16. 5) Pamphlets, publishers' announcements of "Society for the propagation of religious faith," ephemera. 6) Correspondence.
  - Crowley, Aleister, 1875-1947. Papers. Circa 1923 (Box 16)
    Purchase: Sims, 1951.
    "The Drug panic by a London physician," galley proofs with holograph manuscript on reverse. 4 p. See also: Box 15 for Aleister Crowley papers.
  - Crutchley, E. A. 1 als. 1938 Jan 14 (Box 5)
    Removed from: Crutchely, Ernest Addenbrooke. History and description of the Pitt Press. Cambridge, University Press, 1938.
  - Cuney, Waring. Poems., 1960 26 December.; (1 item, 1p. [typescript]). (Box 287, Folder 9)
    Found in an unidentified book.
  - Cunningham, Reverend Alexander. Army of the Potomoc (manuscript)., 1874(?).; (1 item, 262pp. [holograph, unbound]). (Box 281, Folder 3)
    Gift of Merle C. Cunningham.
  - Currie, Mary Montgomery (Lamb) Singleton, Lady, 1843-1905. Autumn songs [London]. 1889 84 p. corrected proofs. (Box 20)
    Purchase Rota, 1853.
    Published Chapman Hall, 1889. With holograph inscription from "Violet Fane," 1889.
  - Curtin, Andrew Gregg, 1815-1894. To S.C. Thomas [?], Harrisburg, Pennsylvania. 1865 February 8 1 p. Holograph signed. (Box 16)
    Recommendation of James Whitaker as a man skilled in the management of iron works. Curtin was Governor of Pennsylvania during the Civil War and owner of iron works in Pennsylvania.
  - Curtis, George William, 1824-1892. Correspondence. circa 1883 4 items. Holograph and typescript. (Box 19)
    1 letter to George Franklin Edmunds, 1883 Feb 17, regarding U. S. Grant and a proposed treaty with Mexico.
  - Curver, Austin. Diary., 1862-1863. (Box 199, Folder 11)
    Civil War experiences written in small bound pocket ledger, with separate leaves from back cover. Photograph from inside front cover.
  - Cushing, Caleb, 1800-1879. Correspondence. 1839-1840 3 pieces. Holograph signed. (Box 31)
    Cushing, Representative from Massachusetts, writes about copy of a report, and an engagement to speak in Portsmouth, Maine. Also to Henry A. S. Dearborn, Newburyport, Massachussetts, 1839 October 14, thanking him for a specimen of a new printing process.
  - Dacre, Barbarina (Ogle) Brand, Baroness, 1767-1854. Letters to various persons. V.p., v.d. 1833-1838 8 items. Holograph. (Box 6)
    4 letters to the Rev. William Harness.
  - Dacre family. Correspondence. V.p., v.d. 1769, 1786, 1821, 1833, ca. 1829 5 items. Holograph. (Box 6)
    1 letter from Anne Dacre, 1789 May 25. 1 letter from Baron Dacre, 1769 March 1. 3 letters from Baron Thomas Dacre, 1821, 1833, Ca. 1829.
  - Dallas, George Mifflin, 1792-1864. To Henry St. George Tucker, Philadelphia. 1839 November 9 2 pp. Holograph signed. (Box 31)
  - Dalton, Peter Roe. To Captain John Gray, Boston. 1788 June 30 1 p. Holograph signed. (Box 16)
  - Daly, Augustin, 1838-1899. Under the gaslight. 1867 93 p. 1v. in paper covers. (Box 15)
    Prompt copy with extensive holograph annotations.
  - Dalye, Charles Patrick, 1816-1899. Letters to various persons, 1869-1893. 5 pieces, holograph signed. (Box 31)
    Daly, New York jurist, writes to President Grant to recommend a friend for judicial appointment, to William M. Evarts concerning Thomas A. Clarke for a justiceship of the Supreme Court, letter concerning literary work, letter concerning Lord Dumaren, and letter concerning a meeting.
  - Daniels, Otis. (Box 4)
    Gift of Hayden L. Hews.
    Collection of 3 legal documents, 1 als, 1 plot plan, 1 account book.
  - Darlington, W[illia]m, 1782-1863. To H[ezekiah] Niles, West Chester [Penn.]. 1831 November 21 2 pages. A.L.S. (Box 9)
  - Davis Ch[arles] Aug[ustus] 1795-1867. Letters to Edward Curtis and [William Henry] Seward. 1839-1840 3 letters. A.L.S. (Box 9)
  - Davis, Henry Winter, 1817-1865. To Isaac Toucey, [Washington]. 1858 December 30 2 p. Holograph signed. (Box 16)
    Davis, Representative from Maryland, recommends a son of Henry A. Thompson of Baltimore as cadet at Annapolis to Toucey, Secretary of the Navy.
  - Davis, John, 1787-1854. To Hezekiah Niles, Washington D. C. 1832 May 12 3 pp. Holograph signed. (Box 31)
    Davis, Representative from Massachusetts, writes to editor Niles about the Tariff reform bill and the influence of the President on that Legislation. References to John S. Barbour, John Clayton, Felix Grundy, and other members of Congress.
  - Davis, John Chandler Bancroft, 1822-1907. Correspondence. 1870-1881 4 pieces, 3 holograph signed. (Box 31)
  - Davis, Noah, 1818-1902. Correspondence. 1865-1892 12 pieces, holograph signed. (Box 31)
    Davis, New York jurist and justice of state Supreme Court, writes of litigation, to Thomas Murphy about an appointment, to Chester A. Arthur as Collector of Port of New York concerning appointment, to Levi P. Morton as minister to France on the same subject, to James Grant Wilson, satiric correspondence about Grover Cleveland, and letters concerning: invitations, personal matters, and reference to United States Grant and Anthony J. Drexel.
  - de Quincy, Thomas, 1785-1859. Manuscript. Holograph, 16 pp, some numbered. In folder. (Box 34)
    Photocopies (negative) from original in Folger Library. Research Grant Fund.
  - De Vere, Aubrey Thomas, 1814-1902. Correspondence. 1 folder. (Box 29)
  - Decatur, Stephen, 1752-1808 ?. To William Whann. 1818 February 4 1 p., holograph signed. (Box 31)
    Possible letter of Decatur, naval hero, on the basis of similarities in letters of the signature, but would have to be misdated. Decatur was killed in the vicinity of Philadelphia in 1808 November. Subject relative to his bank account.
  - DeGraff, John I[saac] 1783-1848. Letters to various persons. 1827-1842 8 letters. (Box 9)
  - Delafield, John, 1748-1824. To Charles Pettit, New York. 1804 April 19 (Box 4)
    Concerning American shipping and the presence of French privateers.
  - DeCasseres, Benjamin. Correspondence and ephemera. (Box 5)
    Gift of H. Richard Archer.
    1 als July 3, 1936. 1 circular reagrding DeCasseres' books. 2 pamphlets by DeCasseres. 1 pamphlet about DeCasseres.
  - Denison, Fred A. 2 invitations for White House receptions, and 1 for D.A. Denison's 75th anniversary., 1900 & 1902.; (3 items, 3pp.). (Box 281, Folder 11)
    All with envelopes (White House invitations with two envelopes each).
  - Depew, Chauncy, 1834-1928. Letter to John P. Nicholson, New York. Also letter from the President of the Missouri Pacific Rail Road. 1894 January 6 and 1893 March 30 2 pieces. Holograph signed. (Box 16)
  - Deukmejian, George. Letter to Sam Glane., 1985. (Box 192, Folder 13)
    re Senate Bill 852.
  - Dickens, Charles, 1812-1870. Correspondence, signed, to various persons. 1848-1870 31 items. Holograph. (Box 30)
    Contents:
    A letter to William Locke, 1848 February 3.
    Letter to Charles Black, 1849 September 28.
    Letter to an unknown lady, 1850 May 7.
    Letter to William Howitt, 1851 April 24.
    Letter to "Dear Sir" (the Mayor of Reading), 1851 October 31.
    Letter to Mrs. Carmichael Smyth, 1857 October 4.
    Letter to T. Crofton Croker, 1851 October 29.
    Letter to Percy Fitzgerald, 1858 August 9.
    Letter to James Payn, 1858 December 6.
    Letter to Miss Jerrold, 1859 June 26.
    Letter to Clarkson Stanfield, 1861 December 10.
    Letter to W. F. de Cerjat, 1862 July 20.
    Letter to Sir Joseph Francis Olliffe, 1863 January 18.
    Letter to Edwin Roffe, 1866 January 18.
    Cancelled check, 1867 January 30.
    Letter to Percy Fitzgerald, 1867 July 21.
    Letter to Henry Bicknell, 1870 March 28.
    Letter to "My Dear Sir," 1844 March 1 [mutilated].
    Letter to Richard A. Brown, 1850 August 31.
    Letter to The Reverend M. Gibson, 1855 January 15.
    Letter to H. P. Smith, 1848 June 21.
    Letter to Edward Chapman, 1852 May 18.
    Cancelled check, 1852 August 19.
    Letter to William Jerdan, 1869 May 15.
    Letter to Charles Smithson, 1841 June 13.
    Letter to Mr. Hamstede, 1855 October 9.
    Letter to Samuel Carter Hall, 1851 February 20, with note from Hall to Henry Stevens at the foot of the page.
    Letter to Samuel Carter Hall, 1851 April 28, with note from Hall to Henry Stevens on reverse of the page.
    Letter to John Forster, 1837 December 11.
    Letter to "My Dear Sir." Doughty Street [London] Monday Evening [before June, 1841].
    Letter to "My Dear Mrs. [George] Cattermole." Office of All the Year Round, 26 Wellington Street, Strand, London, 1868 July 23.
  - Dickinson D[aniel] S[tevens] 1800-1866. Letters to various persons. 1832-1849 3 letters. A.L.S. (Box 9)
  - Dickson, Edward A. Correspondence with Herbert Hoover., 1923-1938.; (Photocopies). (Box 201, Folder 8)
    Telegrams and letters. From Herbert Hoover Library (West Branch, Iowa).
  - Dingley, Nelson Jr., 1832-1899. To Wellington Smith, Washington. 1896 December 21 1 p. Typed letter signed. (Box 16)
    Concerning the Congressional hearing on schedule M of the proposed tariff and Smith's testimony.
  - Dixon, Elizabeth. PhD certificate., 1946. (Box 193, Folder 5)
    PhD in Phenomenology from U. of Bikini, Marshall Islands.
  - Dixon, T. S. E. 1 tls. Ca. 1890s (Box 5)
    Removed from: Dixon, Theron S. E., Francis Bacon and his Shakespeare.
  - Dorscheimer, William, 1832-1888. Correspondence and papers. 1861-1886 7 pieces, holograph signed. (Box 31)
    Dorsheimer, editor of the New York Star and lieutenant governor of New York during the administration of Samuel Tilden, writes of litigation, his newspaper. Manuscript title page to a biography of Grover Cleveland and obituary clipping.
  - Doty, Lockwood Lyon, 1827-1873. To Colonel Schriver, Albany, New York. 1861 August 20 2 pp., holograph signed. (Box 31)
    Doty, private secretary to Governor Fenton of New York, writes about Schriver's resignation, his own bereavement, and the governor's whereabouts.
  - Doubleday, U[lysses] F[reeman] 1792-1866. Letters to Levi Woodbury and George Templeman. 1832 May 18 and 1843 December 21 2 letters. A.L.S. (Box 9)
  - Douglass, Frederick, 1818-1895. To My Dear Friend Theodore, Washington D. C. 1882 September 25 4 pp., holograph signed. (Box 31)
    Douglass speaks of his new book, the political situation, and refers to Benjamin Butler, Elizabeth C. Stanton, Susan B. Anthony, the women's rights movement, and the author of the Swabian Stories.
  - Douglas, George. [Correspondence and papers]. 1911-1935 39 letters and 3 manuscript pieces. (Box 8)
    George Douglas was a book page editor for the William Randolph Hearst newspaper chain in the San Francisco Area.
  - Douglas, Sir George Brisbane, Baronet, 1856-1935. Correspondence, Springwood Park, Kelso. 1926? September 6 1 p. Holograph. (Box 20)
    Removed from "Border Breed and other Poems," London, 1909.
  - Dowell, Marian Griswold (Nevins), 1857-1956. Letters to various persons. V.p., v.d. 1 item. Holograph. (Box 5)
  - Drexel, Anthony Joseph, 1826-1893. Correspondence. 1882-1886 12 pieces.
    Includes responses to a Drexel invitation from Cornelius and [William K.] Vanderbilt, 1882 February 17 and 20.
  - Dubinin, N. P. Experimental investigation of the integration of hereditary systems in the processes of evolution of populations. Zhur. Obshch. Biol. IX(1948), 203-244, translated from the German by I. Michael Lerner. circa 1948 85 leaves typescript (vellum). (Box 25)
  - Duer, W[illiam] 1805-1879. Note. Circa 1847-1851 A.N.S. (Box 9)
  - Dumas, Alexandre, 1824-1895. Correspondence. 2 items. Holograph. (Box 19)
  - Dunhelm, Handley, Correspondence to Mrs. Watkins. 1912 December 23 2 p. Holograph signed. (Box 29)
    Hill purchase: 1955 September 20.
    Dunhelm, Bishop of Durham in 1912, writes to Mrs. Watkins of "Musa Domestica," his brother's volume.
  - Dunkin, John. To John Jones, Philadelphia. 1793 January 24 1 p. Holograph signed. (Box 16)
  - Durant, William James, 1885-1981. Letters to various persons. V.p., v.d. 1966-1967 3 items. Holograph, typescript. (Box 5)
    2 letters to Robert B. Campbell, Campbell's Book Store, Westwood Village.
  - Durrell, Lawrence. 15 letters and 3 telegrams to Cynthia Sears., 1972-1975.; (18 item, 21pp. [typescript, 1 holograph]). (Box 284, Folder 15)
    All on personal letterhead, re daily routine, Miller documentary, Disneyland project, and miscellaneous.
  - Dwinelle, Samuel H. Correspondence. 1879 August 29. 1 page. A.L.S. (Box 8)
    To Edward Maguire, San Francisco, 1879 August 29.
  - Eaton, J[ohn] H[enry] 1790-1856. Letters to John Townsend and to Mrs. Morgan. 1830 April 27 and 1835 September 5 2 letters and one receipt. (Box 9)
    Includes receipt signed by Eaton, 1855 November 6.
  - Eby, H. To Henry O'Reilly, Rochester [New York]. 1835 November 11. 2 pages. A.L.S. (Box 9)
  - Edgeworth, Richard Lovell
  - Edwards, James L. To Nicholas Biddle, Washington D. C. 1824 January 8 1 p., letter signed. (Box 31)
    Edwards, Commissioner of Pensions, informs Biddle, acting as pension agent for Philadelphia, that his report on the subject does not conform to instructions.
  - Einstein, Albert. Facsimile of tls to Mario Palmieri. 1931 Aug 15 (Box 5)
    Gift of Palmieri, October 1949.
  - Electrical Research Products Inc. Operating Instructions for "H" Type Sound Systems. 1931. (Box 29, Folder 45)
  - Elliot, Ebenizer, 1781-1849. Correspondence. 1 piece.
  - Elliot, Robert Brown, 1842-1884. Correspondence. 1871-1873 2 pieces, holograph and letter signed. (Box 31)
    Elliot, Representative from South Carolina, writes in response to requests for aid and information. Addressees' names obscured. Also includes biographical clippings about Elliot, one of the several African American Congressmen in the Reconstruction period.
  - Ellis, Havelock, 1859-1939. Correspondence, signed, to Alphonse James Albert Symons. Henley-on- Thames. 1926 May 16 2 p. Holograph manuscript with envelope. (Box 27)
    Ex libris: C. K. Ogden.
    In this letter, Ellis answers several questions of Symons about a book of his that was suppressed.
  - Emery family. Diaries. 1905 Oct 22-1907 Oct 21 2 v. (notebooks) and 15 l. Ms. (Box 5)
    Gift of Lois Emery Matthews, 1954.
    Diary of Wilhemina (Fowler) Emery covers in two notebooks the first year of her residence in Los Angeles from 1905-1906. In 15 manuscript leaves, her husband Ernest T. Emery records a trip by train from Boston to Los Angeles.
  - English, William Hayden, 1822-1896. To [James C. Dobbin]. 1854 June 1 p. Holograph signed. (Box 16)
    English, Representative from Indiana, recommends Henry Howison of Scott County, Indiana as cadet at Annapolis. Letter probably directed to James C. Dobbin, Secretary of the Navy.
  - Erskine, John, 1879-1951. Correspondence, signed, to William Albert Nitze. 1907-1947 5 items. Holograph and typescript. (Box 27)
    Poem entitled "The Whip-poor-will," signed J. E., appears on the last page of letter dated 1907 December 15.
  - Escalante, Silvestre Valdez de "The destruction of New Mexico.", n.d.; (Holograph, bound). (Box 195, Folder 4)
    Note: "from U.S. Catholic historical magazine 3:73-88."
  - Eustis, William, 1753-1825. Correspondence. 1813 September 25 1item. Holograph. (Box 12)
    1 letter to Richard Cutts.
  - Evans, Edmund, 1826-1905. Correspondence to Thomas Edwards Jones and others. 1897-1904 19 items in 3 folders. Holograph. (Box 17)
    These letters to Mr. Jones are largely concerned with reminiscences of Evans's work with color printing and engraving, as well as the various artists with whom he worked. With these: letter (1909) from Edmund Wilfred Evans (son of Edmund Evans) and three letters (1909) from Mary Evans (wife of Edmund Evans), all to Mr. Jones. With typed transcripts.
  - Evans, Edmund, 1826-1905. Drawings. (English). 1840-1847 34 p. 22.5 x 31.5 cm. Holograph. (Box 20)
    66 watercolor, oil, pen and ink, and pencil sketches, some noted as done at the age of 15 years, mounted in a notebook. Bound in boards with a brown cloth spine. With this: 20 loose items in envelope, including an original pencil sketch of Evans by Birket Foster, and proofs of four prints by Kate Greenaway.
  - Evans, Luther H. Confidential reports to the Librarian (Library of Congress)., 1941-1942.; (2 vol., bound - Typescript carbon). (Box 196, Folder 3)
    Also, correspondence re Evans after his death.
  - Everett, A[lexander] H[ill] 1792-1847. To Artemas Hale, Boston. 1832 August 21 2 pages. A.L.S. (Box 9)
  - Everett, Edward, 1794-1865. Correspondence and clippings. 1826-1858 1 folder. 30 pieces. (Box 25)
    A group of holograph letters by Edward Everett covering the period 1826-1858. Many are to Joseph E. Sprague of Massachusetts, and concern such matter as the presidential campaign of 1828, national political happenings, and literary endeavors. There is also a letter to Alexander H. Stephens and clippings giving historical data on Everett.